If you also want to open a bank account for your child
and are tired of visiting the bank.
But
your child's account is not being opened in the bank.  So
in this video I am giving complete information about
how you
can open a bank account in the name of your child and
after this you can invest it in mutual funds or any other place.  There are
many
parents whose children are
between zero and 18 years of age and
want to open a bank account for their child.  But
when we go to the bank, they say that the
bank account will not be opened.  Even if it is opened,
you will not get an ATM card, cheque book
and due to the absence of all these things,
parents are
not able to invest in mutual funds in the name of their child.
A few days ago I made a detailed
video.  In which I had told
how to invest in mutual funds in the name of the child, in
which many people
contacted me saying that sir, I am
not able to open the bank account.  So in this video
I am giving you complete information.
You guys should watch the video till the end.
Before starting the video, I would like to make a small
request to you that please subscribe to the channel
and like the video because
on our channel you get authentic information about mutual fund
insurance and complete financial planning.
So without wasting any time let's start the
video.  Before moving ahead in the video, let me
tell you that if you
want to invest through us, be it in mutual funds,
through SIP, lump sum or any other
guaranteed investment plan, then
you can contact us.  Let's
start today's video.  Let me tell you
friends, recently RBI had
issued guidelines regarding many bank accounts,
which have also been implemented from June 1, 2025.
Now there will be no problem in opening a bank account in the name of the child.
See, if your child's age is between 10 years to 18
years, then the child can
open his/her own account.  There's
no need for Gjian to be attached to him either.  That
means the child can operate his/her account individually.
And the child will also
get ATM, cheque book, net banking
and all the facilities which
a normal individual gets, which
a normal person above 18 years of age
gets.  Ok?  So these things have come into effect from June 1.
You can
go to your nearest branch and open an account in the name of your child.
But if your
child's age is between zero to 10 years.
What will happen in that case?  In that case, to
open an account in the name of the child,
either the father or the mother will have to
become the guardian.  That means the
child's bank account can be opened only with the guardian.
Ok?  So there is no problem in this also.
If the child's Aadhar card is not made then get it made.  The
birth
certificate must already have been made.  Sometimes a
birth certificate is enough.  There is
no need for Aadhar card also.  Now you
will ask how will the child's Aadhar card
be made?  So let me tell you that even if the child is born, the
Aadhar card of the child can be made.  There is no
problem in that.
Along with making Aadhar card, the guardian's
KYC will be done there.  That means if the
guardian does the biometric then the child's Aadhar card will be made.
Ok?  So two main
documents are required for the child.  Aadhar card and birth
certificate and no other document will be required.
Ok?  And whoever becomes the mother or
father of the relative, their KYC documents will be required
and by going to the bank, their
account can also be opened as a minor account.
Many times banks refuse saying that a
minor account cannot be opened for such a small child.
So there is no such rule that an account cannot be opened for a small child i.e. a
child between zero to 10 years of age.
If any bank
refuses, then talk to them openly about
where we want to invest in mutual funds
and that we want to open an account for our child.
Ok?   It is
possible that the bank
officials may encourage you to
invest in mutual funds through them or if you do so,
you should not fall into their trap because
you will get less returns from there.  So you
can also invest in mutual funds yourself.   You
can invest through an advisor.
You will get more returns from there.  Ok
?  Let me tell you that my daughter is currently one
and a half years old.  But when my daughter was 6
months old, I
opened a bank account for the child.  Ok?  And a
proper ATM card has also been found in it and
SIP is also running in his name.  So this can
definitely happen.  Bank account can be opened.
Ok?
Most people prefer to open a bank account in SBI.
So let me tell you about SBI
that if the bank employee in SBI refuses to
open a bank account, tell him
that I want to open an under guardian account for my child.
Ok?  So,
you get ATM facility very easily in the Under Guardian account.
You can take the ATM.
Get your mobile number linked.  This will
activate your SIP.  There will be no problem.  You
will also get a proper passbook.
The ATM will come to your home.  Although the
facility of minor account for a child is available in every bank, if there is a
lot of work then the bank
officials, clerks, POs,
whoever is looking after the bank work there, do
not want to get into trouble.  Because of this,
you are refused outright.  So you
tell them that no, we need it and we want to get it
opened.  If your work is not getting done from one branch
then go to some other branch and
talk to them or if you have any other
friend or relative then you can contact them also and
if you face any problem anywhere then you can get
your work done.  But
no bank can refuse, we will not open a bank account for the child.
Ok?  So it is a very correct thing.
If you are already aware and
want to invest in the name of your child, then a
bank account is mandatory.  Ok?  You
can open and invest in mutual funds.  There are many direct applications for investing in mutual funds.
So currently there is
no SIP in the name of the minor's child.  So,
if you are facing any problem in opening mutual fund account SIP in the name of your child, then please
contact us.  By
opening your SIP account in online mode, we will make the
investment in your child's name.  So I
hope you liked the video.
Subscribe to the channel for similar videos.  Thank you.